<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Pr56</string>
    <string name="main_page">Main page</string>
    <string name="happy_new_year">Happy New Year</string>
    <string name="new_year_pictures">New Year Images</string>
    <string name="what_is_it_a_page">What is it a page?</string>
    <string name="about_new_year">About New Year</string>
    <string name="new_year_text">New Year is the main calendar holiday that occurs at the moment of transition from the last day of the year to the first day of the next year. It is celebrated by many peoples in accordance with the adopted calendar. The beginning of the year from January 1 was established by the Roman ruler Julius Caesar in 46 BC. In ancient Rome, this day was dedicated to Janus - the god of choice, doors and all beginnings. The month of January got its name in honor of the god Janus, who was depicted with two faces: one looking forward and the other looking back. Most countries celebrate New Year on January 1, the first day of the year in the Gregorian calendar. Standard Time New Year\'s Eve always begins in the Pacific Ocean on the islands of Kiribati. The last to see off the old year are the inhabitants of the Midway Islands in the Pacific Ocean. Some countries celebrate the New Year according to the lunar calendar. From January 1, New Year is first celebrated in 153 BC. e., since from that day the Roman consuls took office. In 46 BC. e. Roman general and high priest Guy Julius Caesar introduced his new calendar (\"Julian\") and finally approved the beginning of the year from January 1, 45 BC. e. It was under Caesar that, under the influence of astrology, the New Year\'s holiday acquired an independent meaning as a time mark for the beginning of the year and, thus, marked the beginning of the civil year. When celebrating the New Year, various pyrotechnic products are actively used: firecrackers, sparklers and, in the last decade, fireworks, rockets, Roman candles, small and large firecrackers, etc. The use of pyrotechnic products for celebrating the New Year began in Asian countries, and, in first of all, in China, since it was believed that the loud noise and bright light received from the explosions of gunpowder made it possible to ward off evil spirits. Later, this tradition spread throughout the world. The most famous tradition in different countries, formed due to superstition, is the lighting of fireworks in China for the New Year, as well as explosions of firecrackers, which do not stop throughout the first New Year\'s day. At the same time, gunpowder itself, firecrackers and fireworks were invented not so long ago, but a thousand-year history is attributed to the tradition of creating noise and din when celebrating the New Year. It all started with the legend that on New Year\'s Eve, evil spirits, expelled from different places, are looking for a new home, and having found a suitable house, they settle in it and throughout the coming year they will fix various troubles for the owners. The noise at the meeting of the New Year is intended to drive away evil from the house. Nowadays, many capitals of the world or even individual countries spend millions of dollars to put on a pyrotechnic show for the New Year. The use of pyrotechnic products in large quantities, including by minors, creates a potentially fire hazardous and traumatic situation, therefore New Year\'s Eve is considered the most stressful period of the year in the work of firefighting and rescue services.</string>
</resources>